# 哈喽 大家好我是王刚
Hello, everyone. I'm Wang Gang.
# 关于上一次我们去扬州收获了很多
I have learnt a lot last time went to Yangzhou.
# 一个星期左右
About a week.
# 尝了很多扬州的美食
I've tried a lot of Yangzhou food.
# 其中有一道扬州炒饭让我特别印象深刻
I was particularly impressed by the Yangzhou fried rice.
# 因为这个炒饭的话在我们这边
In restaurants in Sichuan, the typical price of that fried rice
# 一般价格就是10-38块不等
is somewhere from 10-38 yuan.
# 如果说上了30块以上的话里面肯定是有虾仁
If it's more than 30 yuan, there must be shrimp in it.
# 还有一些火腿啊
And some ham.
# 还有一些青豆啊玉米粒啊之类的
And some green beans or corns kernel etc.
# 然后我在扬州这段时间我吃了很多家
I have ordered fried rice in many restaurants while I was in Yangzhou.
# 他们便宜的都最少是38
They're all at least 38 yuan.
# 然后贵的可以卖到100多200多
And the expensive ones can go for 100s or 200s yuan.
# 那这一次呢也算是搞清楚了
Well, this time it's all clear for me.
# 它这里面有什么配料
What's in it?
# 就是我们去扬州这边吃了这个炒饭之后
We went to Yangzhou to eat the fried rice.
# 里面有什么配料 它为什么卖那么贵
What's in it? Why is it so expensive?
# 然后这次我买了一些做扬州炒饭的一些料回来
So this time I bought some ingredients to make Yangzhou fried rice.
# 准备按照官方给的一个标准做一份来试一下
I'm going to try to make it according to an official standard.
# 这一次我们来看一下啊
Let's take a look at this one.
# 我们便宜的扬州炒饭里面说的火腿
Some said the ham in the cheap Yangzhou fried rice is
# 有的是加午餐肉有的是加火腿肠
either luncheon meat or ham hocks.
# 其实这个都不对的
Actually, that's not the right way to do it.
# 因为怎么说呢
Because...
# 扬州炒饭里面的火腿它其实是这种
The ham in Yangzhou fried rice is actually this kind of ham.
# 是类似于是这种
It's something like that.
# 这个是金华火腿
This is Jinhua ham.
# 这个是用来吊高汤用的
It's usually used to make stock.
# 然后
Then,
# 专门用来做扬州炒饭的是这个
This is the one used to make Yangzhou fried rice.
# 这根是宣威火腿
This is a Xuanwei ham.
# 宣威火腿的话就肉没有那么咸
It's not that salty.
# 就是宣威这个地方常年的是在
It's just that this place, Xuanwei, is
# 高原吧
in highland.
# 应该说是高原比较干燥比较冷
I'd say it's drier and colder in the highlands.
# 然后它这个火腿盐分要淡一些
So there is less salt in their ham.
# 如果说在我们四川这边也用这个盐量来的话
If we use the same amount of salt here in Sichuan...
# 这个肉会臭
This meat will stink.
# 然后这个的话肉比较香
And this one is more fragrant.
# 扬州炒饭里面的原材料火腿其实讲的就是这个猪腿
The ingredients in Yangzhou fried rice is actually this pork leg ham.
# 在我们这里像这种不管你是金华火腿还是宣威火腿
Here, it doesn't matter if you use a Jinhua ham or a Xuanwei ham,
# 也通通称为腊肉
They're all called cured meat.
# 所以这个金华火腿适合用来吊汤
This Jinhua ham is better for making stock.
# 之前有粉丝他可能说用火腿吊汤用了这种
One of my fans told me he might have used one of these to make stock,
# 这种午餐肉或者是火腿肠拿去吊汤
like lunchmeat or ham hock. Take those to make the stock.
# 他拿来煮里面就会发浑 然后味道也不是很好
When he cooked it, it got mushy, and it didn't taste very good.
# 所以火腿的话
As for the ham,
# 大家一直有一个误区
There's always been a misunderstanding.
# 就认为这种是火腿
Just think of it as ham.
# 实际上这种就是在店子里面的话在一些小餐馆
In fact, it's the kind of thing you'd find in some small restaurant.
# 为了把成本控下来
They use this to keep the costs down.
# 他一般不会说去买这种火腿来
They don't usually going to buy this ham.
# 我们这个火腿的话
This ham.
# 现在的价格是60块钱一斤
It's 60 yuan per jin (500g) now.
# 但是这个宣威火腿要更贵一点大概68的样子
But this Xuanwei ham is a little more expensive, about 68.
# 所以为了这一次能够拍好这个扬州炒饭
So in order to get a good shot of this Yangzhou fried rice...
# 我们下了血本买了一根火腿
We bought the whole ham.
# 一根宣威火腿一根金华火腿这两根大概加起来1600
One Xuanwei ham and one Jinhua ham. The two add up to about 1600 yuan.
# 然后还买了海参
And then I bought some sea cucumbers.
# 这个海参
This sea cucumber.
# 还有这个
And this.
# 瑶柱
Dried scallops
# 这个
This one
# 我买的这个大概有小指头那么大
The one I bought is about the size of my pinky.
# 这个是180一斤
This one is 180 yuan per jin (500g).
# 然后这个海参的话就偏贵一点
And the sea cucumber is a bit more expensive.
# 我买的这个是淡干海参自己泡发
The one I bought is dried sea cucumber, you need to soak them.
# 如果你们嫌麻烦的话可以直接买那种冻的
If you think it's too much trouble, you can just buy the frozen ones.
# 就是拿回来解冻就可以吃的那种
You know, the kind you take back and defrost and eat.
# 最后一点就是关于我们买这么大的火腿一时吃不完怎么办
One last thing about what if we buy this big ham and we don't eat it all at once.
# 这个火腿的话我建议大家把它砍成小块
For this ham, I suggest you cut it into small pieces.
# 然后用保鲜膜封起来放冰箱
Then seal it in plastic wrap and put it in the fridge.
# 可以放一年左右
It's good for about a year.
# 像这种比较湿的火腿
A wetter ham like this one.
# 最好是用油给它封住然后再用保鲜膜给它包起来放到冰箱
It's best to seal it with oil and then wrap it in plastic wrap and put it in the fridge.
# 好了 现在这些原材料已经介绍完了
Okay, now we're done with the raw materials.
# 就是花了几千块钱买了这么多东西
That's all the stuff we bought for the following dishes.
# 这个金华火腿我用了它来做一个传统的开水白菜
This Jinhua ham, I will use it to make a traditional Sichuan boiled cabbage.
# 用它来吊高汤
Use it to make delicious stock.
# 然后这个宣威火腿我用它的肉来做一个官方给出的一个标准
And then this Xuanwei ham I will use its meat to make an official standard...
# 做一份扬州炒饭
Yangzhou fried rice.
# 好吧 本期视频到这里
All right, that's it for this video.
# 大家期待一下我后面的开水白菜跟扬州炒饭
Look forward to my cabbage and Yangzhou fried rice later.
# 就到这里 拜拜
That's it. Bye.